<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Boston Women in Bioinformatics&apos;s Events</title><description>Stay updated with our upcoming events and meetups</description><link>https://boston-wib.org</link><item><title>Building Adaptive Strategies for Career Advancement in Science</title><link>https://boston-wib.org//events/event20251210</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://boston-wib.org//events/event20251210</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When:&lt;/strong&gt; Wednesday, December 10, 2025 at 5:00 PM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where:&lt;/strong&gt; Zoom Webinar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This event is co-hosted by &lt;a href=&quot;https://boston-wib.org&quot;&gt;Boston-Area Women in Bioinformatics (BWIB)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.felstedcoaching.com&quot;&gt;Felsted Coaching &amp;amp; Consulting&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your career is your most personal experiment, requiring both strategic thinking and adaptive flexibility. Linear career trajectories are giving way to &amp;quot;squiggly&amp;quot; paths that demand updated approaches to advancement in today’s evolving scientific landscape. This session will equip you with a framework to navigate career advancement with intention.
Dr. Jenn Felsted-Knight, former neuroscientist turned leadership coach, will introduce her signature ADAPT framework designed to help you clarify your goals and unique value proposition, create a roadmap that evolves with changing priorities, and apply systematic approaches to career decision-making. We&amp;#39;ll explore key factors including building visibility for your work, developing strategic relationships, and creating sustainable advancement strategies that integrate with your life priorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the framework presentation, the session will include dedicated time for your questions, creating space to apply the framework to your specific career challenges and learn from each other&amp;#39;s experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join us on August 12th&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded><category>CareerDevelopment</category><category>TechCareers</category><category>ProfessionalDevelopment</category><category>CareerStrategy</category><category>JobSeeker</category><category>WomenInBioinformatics</category><category>WomenInSTEM</category></item></channel></rss>