<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Boston Women in Bioinformatics&apos;s Events</title><description>Stay updated with our upcoming events and meetups</description><link>https://boston-wib.org</link><item><title>New Year, New Connections Social</title><link>https://boston-wib.org//events/event20260115</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://boston-wib.org//events/event20260115</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 22:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When:&lt;/strong&gt; Thursday, January 15, 2026 at 10:30 PM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where:&lt;/strong&gt; C-Side Bar, CambridgeSide, 100 Cambridgeside Pl, Cambridge, Massachusetts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you a bioinformatics enthusiast looking to meet and mingle with fellow professionals in a relaxed and unscripted environment? Join us for a relaxed, no-pressure social event designed for one thing: connecting with other women in bioinformatics. There&amp;#39;s no formal program or presentations—just an opportunity to have real conversations, expand your network, and meet the people who make up Boston&amp;#39;s vibrant bioinformatics community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;ll have exclusive 10-year anniversary swag available for anyone who missed our recent celebration. We&amp;#39;re also working on arranging professional headshots with a photographer, perfect timing for refreshing your LinkedIn profile or website. More details on photo sessions coming soon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​Whether you&amp;#39;re looking to make new professional connections, reconnect with colleagues, or simply spend an evening with ladies who understand what &amp;quot;debugging a Nextflow pipeline&amp;quot; means, we&amp;#39;d love to see you there. Since the bar is located in a food court, feel free to grab dinner or snacks—you&amp;#39;re not limited to just drinks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​Come as you are. Stay as long as you&amp;#39;d like (until 9pm when the mall closes). Leave with new connections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What to Know Before You Register&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This event is intended for individuals who identify as &lt;span class=&quot;underline decoration-double&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thetrevorproject.org/resources/category/gender-identity/&quot;&gt;women&lt;/a&gt; and gender-diverse individuals &lt;/span&gt;. 👩‍🔬&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each guest will be responsible for purchasing their own meal and/or beverages. 🍽️&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to find us&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll be gathering at the C-Side Bar in the CambridgeSide Mall food court, a lively and accessible spot right in the heart of East Cambridge. If you&amp;#39;re taking the MBTA Green Line, hop off at Lechmere Station—it’s just a short walk to the mall entrance. Driving in? The mall offers plenty of garage parking with flexible hourly rates and extended hours, so you’ll have no trouble finding a spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The food court features a variety of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cambridgeside.com/event/canalside-food-drink/2145582916&quot;&gt;dining options&lt;/a&gt;, so feel free to grab a bite, a beverage, and stay awhile!&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded><category>byteandbite</category></item></channel></rss>