<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Boston Women in Bioinformatics&apos;s Events</title><description>Stay updated with our upcoming events and meetups</description><link>https://boston-wib.org</link><item><title>Communicate Your Unique Value: A Masterclass for Job Seekers</title><link>https://boston-wib.org//events/event20251204</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://boston-wib.org//events/event20251204</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When:&lt;/strong&gt; Thursday, December 4, 2025 at 5:00 PM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where:&lt;/strong&gt; Zoom Webinar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​Ever walked into an interview or networking event and struggled to clearly articulate what makes you exceptional? You&amp;#39;re not alone. In today&amp;#39;s competitive job market, it&amp;#39;s not always the most skilled who rise—it&amp;#39;s the ones who can communicate their value with clarity and confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​Join us for this interactive masterclass with career coach Joanna Ghayad, where you&amp;#39;ll learn to transform your technical achievements into a compelling value statement that gets you noticed, respected, and sought after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;​In this one-hour session, you&amp;#39;ll&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;​Uncover your hidden strengths through guided self-assessment exercises&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;​Learn from real-world case studies of successful career positioning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;​Create your personal unique value statement&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gain frameworks for confidently presenting yourself in interviews and networking settings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;​Receive tools and resources to continue refining your professional narrative&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;​Who should attend&lt;/strong&gt;: Scientists and bioinformaticians who are navigating the job market, seeking career advancement, or want to position themselves more effectively in their field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​Walk away with a clear, memorable statement of your unique value and the confidence to share it in any professional setting. No more rambling about achievements or underselling yourself—just authentic, compelling communication that opens doors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;​About the speaker&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://joannaghayadcoaching.com/&quot;&gt;Joanna Ghayad&lt;/a&gt; is a certified career coach with 15+ years of experience in pharma, academia, and biotech. She specializes in helping scientists build portfolio careers and communicate their value with confidence. Joanna created a leadership development program at BMS that&amp;#39;s now in its 5th year and has completed over 500 hours of coaching.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded><category>CareerDevelopment</category><category>CareerCoach</category><category>ProfessionalDevelopment</category><category>CareerStrategy</category></item><item><title>Building Adaptive Strategies for Career Advancement in Science</title><link>https://boston-wib.org//events/event20251210</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://boston-wib.org//events/event20251210</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When:&lt;/strong&gt; Wednesday, December 10, 2025 at 5:00 PM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where:&lt;/strong&gt; Zoom Webinar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This event is co-hosted by &lt;a href=&quot;https://boston-wib.org&quot;&gt;Boston-Area Women in Bioinformatics (BWIB)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.felstedcoaching.com&quot;&gt;Felsted Coaching &amp;amp; Consulting&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your career is your most personal experiment, requiring both strategic thinking and adaptive flexibility. Linear career trajectories are giving way to &amp;quot;squiggly&amp;quot; paths that demand updated approaches to advancement in today’s evolving scientific landscape. This session will equip you with a framework to navigate career advancement with intention.
Dr. Jenn Felsted-Knight, former neuroscientist turned leadership coach, will introduce her signature ADAPT framework designed to help you clarify your goals and unique value proposition, create a roadmap that evolves with changing priorities, and apply systematic approaches to career decision-making. We&amp;#39;ll explore key factors including building visibility for your work, developing strategic relationships, and creating sustainable advancement strategies that integrate with your life priorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the framework presentation, the session will include dedicated time for your questions, creating space to apply the framework to your specific career challenges and learn from each other&amp;#39;s experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join us on August 12th&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded><category>CareerDevelopment</category><category>TechCareers</category><category>ProfessionalDevelopment</category><category>CareerStrategy</category><category>JobSeeker</category><category>WomenInBioinformatics</category><category>WomenInSTEM</category></item></channel></rss>