<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Boston Women in Bioinformatics&apos;s Events</title><description>Stay updated with our upcoming events and meetups</description><link>https://boston-wib.org</link><item><title>Byte and Bite: Bioinformatics Lunch Meetup</title><link>https://boston-wib.org//events/event20251107</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://boston-wib.org//events/event20251107</guid><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When:&lt;/strong&gt; Friday, November 7, 2025 at 12:00 PM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where:&lt;/strong&gt; CanalSide Food &amp; Drink, CambridgeSide, 100 Cambridgeside Pl, Cambridge, Massachusetts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you a bioinformatics enthusiast looking to meet and mingle with fellow professionals in a relaxed and unscripted environment? Join us for a Bioinformatics Networking Lunch, an informal gathering where great conversations, shared ideas, and new connections are on the menu!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What to Know Before You Register&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This gathering is intended for individuals who identify as &lt;span class=&quot;underline decoration-double&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thetrevorproject.org/resources/category/gender-identity/&quot;&gt;women&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. 👩‍🔬&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each guest will be responsible for purchasing their own meal and/or beverages. 🍽️&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How to find us&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll be gathering at the CambridgeSide Mall food court, a lively and accessible spot right in the heart of East Cambridge. If you&amp;#39;re taking the MBTA Green Line, hop off at Lechmere Station—it’s just a short walk to the mall entrance. Driving in? The mall offers plenty of garage parking with flexible hourly rates and extended hours, so you’ll have no trouble finding a spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​Once inside, head toward Chilacates—we’ll be nearby! The food court features a variety of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cambridgeside.com/event/canalside-food-drink/2145582916&quot;&gt;dining options&lt;/a&gt;, so feel free to grab a bite, explore, and settle in.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded><category>byteandbite</category></item><item><title>GitHub Basics 2</title><link>https://boston-wib.org//events/event20251113</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://boston-wib.org//events/event20251113</guid><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 17:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When:&lt;/strong&gt; Thursday, November 13, 2025 at 5:30 PM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where:&lt;/strong&gt; Boynton Yards, Somerville, MA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ready to level up your GitHub skills? GitHub Basics 2 builds on the foundations from our first session and dives deeper into collaborative coding skills like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Branching and pull requests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolving merge conflicts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using issues and discussions to communicate code changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a hands-on, beginner-friendly workshop designed to help you gain confidence with GitHub workflows, whether you’re contributing to open source, managing your own projects, or collaborating with a team. A basic understanding of making commits and working with remotes is required. If you didn&amp;#39;t attend our first GitHub basics workshop, please review the material for making commits &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sstein93/git-github-workshop/blob/main/02_git_basics.md&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and working with remotes &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sstein93/git-github-workshop/blob/main/03_git_github.md&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parking is $10 at Boynton yards if you park after 5pm, and there may be street parking on Cambridge street or other nearby streets&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded><category>github</category></item></channel></rss>