<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Boston Women in Bioinformatics&apos;s Events</title><description>Stay updated with our upcoming events and meetups</description><link>https://boston-wib.org</link><item><title>New Year, New Connections Social</title><link>https://boston-wib.org//events/event20260115</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://boston-wib.org//events/event20260115</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 22:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When:&lt;/strong&gt; Thursday, January 15, 2026 at 10:30 PM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where:&lt;/strong&gt; C-Side Bar, CambridgeSide, 100 Cambridgeside Pl, Cambridge, Massachusetts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you a bioinformatics enthusiast looking to kick off the new year by meeting and mingling with fellow professionals in a relaxed and unscripted environment? Join us for a relaxed, no-pressure social event designed for one thing: connecting with others in the bioinformatics community. There&amp;#39;s no formal program or presentations—just an opportunity to have real conversations, expand your network, and meet the people who make up Boston&amp;#39;s vibrant bioinformatics community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this event focuses on supporting women and gender-diverse individuals in bioinformatics, allies are welcome to join us. If you&amp;#39;re attending as an ally, please review our &lt;a href=&quot;#ally&quot;&gt;ally guidelines&lt;/a&gt; below to help make this the supportive, inclusive space we&amp;#39;re building together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we step into 2026, we want to hear your vision for the year ahead! Come ready to share ideas for events you&amp;#39;d like to see, community initiatives you&amp;#39;d like to contribute to, or tools and resources you wish existed in the bioinformatics space. Let&amp;#39;s start the new year by building new connections and shaping what our community does next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How to find us:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll be gathering at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.csidebar.com/&quot;&gt;C-Side Bar&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cambridgeside.com/canalside&quot;&gt;CambridgeSide Mall food court&lt;/a&gt;, a lively and accessible spot right in the heart of East Cambridge. If you&amp;#39;re taking the MBTA Green Line, hop off at Lechmere Station—it’s just a short walk to the mall entrance. Driving in? The mall offers plenty of garage parking with flexible hourly rates and extended hours, so you’ll have no trouble finding a spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The food court features a variety of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cambridgeside.com/event/canalside-food-drink/2145582916&quot;&gt;dining options&lt;/a&gt;, so feel free to grab a bite, a beverage, and stay awhile!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;ally&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Guidelines for Allies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We welcome allies to join us in supporting women in bioinformatics! Your presence helps build a more inclusive community. Most of this is probably obvious to you, but it&amp;#39;s easy to fall into old habits in professional settings, so here&amp;#39;s a friendly reminder of how to be most supportive:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to be an ally&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is primarily a space for women to connect, share experiences, and support each other. As an ally, focus on listening and learning rather than being the center of attention. Contribute thoughtfully to conversations, but leave plenty of space for women&amp;#39;s voices - aim to listen more than you speak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;​How to contribute positively&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Invite women colleagues who would benefit from this community - arriving together can make it easier for newcomers to join in, and you&amp;#39;ll help us grow the network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ask thoughtful questions rather than offering unsolicited advice or explanations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;​If someone shares their expertise or experience, trust it - avoid the urge to explain or debate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;​When women share experiences of bias or challenges, listen and validate rather than offering alternative explanations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;​Help make introductions between people with shared professional interests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;​If you notice someone standing alone or between conversations, invite them to join yours: &amp;quot;We&amp;#39;re talking about [topic], would you like to join us?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;​What to avoid:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;​Interrupting women who are speaking&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;​Taking up speaking opportunities or networking slots meant for women attendees&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;​Lengthy monologues or centering your own perspectives in discussions about gender equity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;photographer&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Calling photographers!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interested in taking professional headshots for a future event? We&amp;#39;re open to various arrangements - volunteer opportunity for portfolio building, partial compensation, or paid services. Contact the event organizers or reach out to us at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:Bostonwomeninbioinformatics@gmail.com&quot;&gt;Bostonwomeninbioinformatics@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; and let&amp;#39;s find something that works for both of us.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded><category>byteandbite</category></item><item><title>Career Possibilities Panel &amp; Speed Networking - Legal including General Counsel, Patents, and Intellectual Property</title><link>https://boston-wib.org//events/west20260129</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://boston-wib.org//events/west20260129</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When:&lt;/strong&gt; Thursday, January 29, 2026 at 11:00 PM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where:&lt;/strong&gt; Zoom&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the STEM landscape continues to evolve, professionals are increasingly embracing non-linear career paths that reflect their expanding skills, interests, and goals. This series is designed to support STEM professionals navigating career shifts—whether exploring new sectors, pursuing leadership roles, or transitioning into emerging fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The panel will have an informational interview type feel with panelists sharing their career paths, a look at what their job entails, and transferable skills for those looking to make a change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Panelists to Include&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/thanh-erion/&quot;&gt;Thanh Erion&lt;/a&gt; - Senior Counsel, Intellectual Property at AbbVie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/angelyn-larkin-8b594b8a/&quot;&gt;Angelyn Larkin&lt;/a&gt; - Patent Attorney at Lando &amp;amp; Anastasi, LLP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;Vidya Subramanian&lt;/u&gt; - General Counsel at Souffle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agenda&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 mins: Welcome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;60 mins: Panel discussion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;12 mins: Small-group speed networking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 mins: Learnings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;12 mins: Small-group speed networking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded><category>WEST</category></item><item><title>Byte and Bite: Bioinformatics Lunch Meetup</title><link>https://boston-wib.org//events/event20260213</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://boston-wib.org//events/event20260213</guid><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When:&lt;/strong&gt; Friday, February 13, 2026 at 5:00 PM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where:&lt;/strong&gt; CanalSide Food &amp; Drink, CambridgeSide, 100 Cambridgeside Pl, Cambridge, Massachusetts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Celebrate Galentine&amp;#39;s Day with your fellow bioinformatics besties! Whether you&amp;#39;re already part of our community or looking to make new connections, join us for a relaxed lunch where women and all gender minorities can meet, mingle, and share ideas over good food and great conversation. Treat yourself to an afternoon of professional networking wrapped in Galentine&amp;#39;s Day spirit!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What to Know Before You Register&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This gathering is intended for individuals who identify as &lt;span class=&quot;underline decoration-double&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thetrevorproject.org/resources/category/gender-identity/&quot;&gt;women&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. 👩‍🔬&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each guest will be responsible for purchasing their own meal and/or beverages. 🍽️&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How to find us&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll be gathering at the CambridgeSide Mall food court, a lively and accessible spot right in the heart of East Cambridge. If you&amp;#39;re taking the MBTA Green Line, hop off at Lechmere Station—it’s just a short walk to the mall entrance. Driving in? The mall offers plenty of garage parking with flexible hourly rates and extended hours, so you’ll have no trouble finding a spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​Once inside, head toward Chilacates—we’ll be nearby! The food court features a variety of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cambridgeside.com/event/canalside-food-drink/2145582916&quot;&gt;dining options&lt;/a&gt;, so feel free to grab a bite, explore, and settle in.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded><category>byteandbite</category></item></channel></rss>